Guénolé FICHE

10, rue Alfred de Musset 91120 Palaiseau, France guenole.fiche@gmail.com (+33) 6 51 36 24 77

www.linkedin.com/in/Guenole-Fiche

https://g-fiche.github.io/ https://github.com/g-fiche



26 years old

PhD Student in computer vision - CentraleSupelec Anticipated graduation date: 10/24

My research focuses on Computer Vision and Deep Learning. I work on 3D human pose and shape estimation from images and videos, with a focus on weakly-supervised methods (generative models, self-supervised learning).

Education

•	Since 2021	PhD student in computer vision – CentraleSupelec (France) Subject: Learned latent representations for human mesh recovery
		Keywords: Pytorch, (D-)VAE, VQ-VAE, MAE, digital humans, SMPL, 3D vision
•	2016-2021	Mathematic Engineering department – INSA Rouen Normandie (France)
		Keywords: AI, Machine Learning, optimization, statistics
•	June 2016	Science Baccalaureate – European section – Graduate with High Honors

Work experience

• 2023	Visiting PhD Student - Institut de robòtica i informàtica industrial (Spain)
	Exchange in the "Perception and manipulation" group
• 2022 - 2023	Tutorial Assistant – INSA Rennes (France)
	Geometry tutorials for second year students of engineering (Curves and surfaces, integrals)
• 2021	Deep Learning 6 months internship – Polynom (France)
	Multi-object detection and tracking
	Keywords: Python, Pytorch, YOLOv5, optical flow, Kalman Filter, GPS, orthophotos,
• Summer 20	NLP 3 months internship – Case Law Analytics (France)
	Natural Language Processing methods applied to automated analysis of legal texts
	Keywords: Python, Tensorflow, BERT, Regex, k-means, ACP, similarity, NLI
• Summer 20	Deep Learning 3 months research internship – University of British Columbia (Canada)
	Exploring the Application of Machine Learning for Physical Problem
	Keywords: Python, Tensorflow, Deep Learning, LSTM, ML for physics, composite materials
• 2019-2021	Sales manager and project leader - Junior Enterprise of the INSA Rouen (France)

Publications

- Fiche, G., Leglaive, S., Alameda-Pineda, X., & Moreno-Noguer, F. 2024. MEGA: Masked Generative Autoencoder for Human Mesh Recovery. https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.18839
- Fiche, G., Leglaive, S., Alameda-Pineda, X., Agudo, A., & Moreno-Noguer, F. 2024. VQ-HPS: Human Pose and Shape Estimation in a Vector-Quantized Latent Space. In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV).
- Fiche, G., Leglaive, S., Alameda-Pineda, X., and Séguier, R. 2023. "Motion-DVAE: Unsupervised learning for fast human motion denoising." ACM SIGGRAPH Conference on Motion, Interaction and Games (MIG '23).
- Fiche, G., Sevestre, V., Gonzalez-Barral, C., Leglaive, S., and Séguier, R. 2023. SwimXYZ: "A large-scale dataset of synthetic swimming motions and videos." 16th ACM SIGGRAPH Conference on Motion, Interaction and Games (MIG '23).

Skills

Languages: English (TOEIC test: 965) and Spanish (Advanced)

Programming: Python (Pytorch and Tensorflow) - Notions of: R, Matlab, Java, C, C++, SQL Areas of expertise: Deep learning (VAE, dynamic models, probabilistic AI), 3D computer vision

Generative models, weakly-supervised and self-supervised learning

Virtual humans, pose and shape estimation, human motion.

Courses: Machine Learning (Coursera) – Andrew Ng, Stanford

English for research, Research communication ethics, Bayesian Data fusion

Summer schools: Generative Modeling Summer School, Copenhagen, June 2023

Sport and IA, Antibes, October 2022

Hobbies Other experiences

Sports: Tennis, Volleyball, Running...

Music: Musical education and guitar practice

Music studies section - INSA de Rouen

Language learning: Hindi

2022 Reviewing

ECCV, CVPR, NeurIPS

July 2018 European Solidarity Corps - Spain

Tourism information counsellor

2018-2019 Volunteer Tutoring in mathematics

Help in mathematics for INSA students